# Joseph Micucci

# micucci.joseph@gmail.com

317-412-3412 • Indianapolis, IN

linkedin.com/in/josephmicucci93/ • https://jjomic.github.io/Portfolio/

### **Objective:**

I'm a former retail lifer turned tech professional who has been described by peers as a "facilitator" in team-based scenarios. I'm always trying to find ways to combine my technical skills with the people skills I've gained through years of previous experience to help find the avenues that lead to the success of my clients, my team, and myself.

#### **Education:**

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Software Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, December 2021
  - 12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, realworld project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training
  - o *Eleven Fifty Core Value Award: Teamwork.* Voted by my classmates as the individual who most exemplified a commitment to working together as one in utilizing the team's combined strengths to achieve a shared vision.
- Roncalli High School, Indianapolis, IN, May 2012

#### **Competencies & Functional Skills:**

Problem solving, troubleshooting, creativity, visual & verbal communication, customer service, critical observation and thinking, organization, Agile methodology, portfolio development, addressing and resolving business challenges, knowing when to take charge and when to let others take charge in a team environment.

#### **Technical Skills:**

Languages/Libraries: C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript ES6, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum

**Technologies:** G-Suite, Slack, Zoom, Loom, Notion, HubSpot, Salesforce, Atlassian

Certifications: Google Project Management, MTA: Software Development Fundamentals, Webflow 101

### **Professional Experience:**

# Customer Success Manager, Ninetailed, USA (Remote), October 2022 - May 2023

- Ninetailed's first Customer Success Manager that was tasked with building out the CS department from the ground up.
- Built call structures for Pre-Sales to Post Sales Handoff, Client Kickoff, Client Training, and regularly scheduled check-in calls.
- Built Company's first Client Ticket Portal using Atlassian.
  - o Worked with product and engineering teams to create ticketing workflow as well as escalation standards.
- Helped clients, primarily B2C & B2B eCommerce brands, operationalize testing and keeping them informed on best personalization practices across multiple channels.

### Technical Customer Success Manager, Wicked Reports, USA (Remote), March 2022 – June 2022

- Project managed clients, mainly mid-size B2C eCommerce brands, during the onboarding process by conducting setup, data analysis, and technical troubleshooting conference calls as well as answering client e-mails, creating/monitoring support tickets, & managing the client's deal page/notes within HubSpot.
- Part of an internal team in our department whose primary focus was increasing client engagement via gaining insight into user intelligence through metrics acquired from the UX & UI walkthroughs developed by this team. This also included QA Testing/Troubleshooting on these walkthroughs before and after they went live.
- Starting June 2022 was part of a beta team that focused solely on the Onboarding & Integration of clients to the platform. Calls centered around making sure connections to the platform were operating properly as well as base-level data validation to ensure we were pulling data correctly.

### Account Specialist, Tangoe INC, Indianapolis, IN November 2020 - August 2021

- Handled business to business relationships between cell phone carriers and their corporate clientele.
  - o Including, but not limited to technical support for cellular devices, making inquiries about a client's bill, and the ordering/replacement of cellular devices.
  - The focus of this job was to be the face that end users saw when they interacted with Tangoe, and to also be the liaison between the end user, Tangoe, and the cellular service provider.

### Telephone Sales Representative, Guitar Center, Indianapolis, IN April 2020 - November 2020

- Handling incoming sales/customer service calls
- Handling outbound sales/customer service calls with higher emphasis on sales calls.
- Also dealt with contacting customers via e-mail

# Homeowner Customer Care Outbound Specialist, Angi, Indianapolis, IN October 2018 - March 2020

- Outbound calls to homeowners regarding requests they had made through the Angie's List (now Angi) website and following up on the status of them.
- Sales aspect that revolved around inquiring about any additional projects around the house that the homeowners were looking to start.
- Occasional follow up with homeowners via e-mail, but mainly phone contact.

### Retail Operations Lead, Guitar Center, Columbus, OH September 2016 – July 2018

- Oversaw daily handling of store's money deposit making sure all money from the previous day was in order.
- The department, in general, dealt with shipping orders out from the store; preparing the store for opening every morning; and organizing the store's warehouse inventory.
- Initially started as an Operations Associate but was promoted to Lead in February 2017.

### Telephone Customer Support Representative, Guitar Center, Indianapolis, IN April 2015 – August 2016

- Handled inbound Customer Service and Sales Calls, with emphasis on Customer Service.
  - o Still had sales quotas to maintain, however.
- Handled live chat and email support for Guitar Center's website.

#### Convenience Store Clerk, Walgreens, Greenwood, IN April 2010 – April 2015

- Basic, front end clerk responsibilities (stocking shelves, checking out customers, cleaning store lobby, etc.)
- Cross-trained as a photo clerk in February 2013 and alternated between front end and photo for the remainder of my time at Walgreens.